Xiaotian Han

Ph.D. Student Department of Computer Science & Engineering Texas A&M University

exas A&M University Homepage: ahxt.github.io

E-mail: han@tamu.edu

Research Interests

I am a 4th-year Ph.D. student in the Department of Computer Science and Engineering at Texas A&M University. I am working at the DATA Lab under the supervision of Prof. Xia (Ben) Hu. My research focuses on graph learning, fairness in machine learning, and automated machine learning. Specifically, my research lies in the following topics:

- **Graph Learning**: large-scale graph neural networks, graph augmentation
- Fairness: egocentric fairness and structure fairness in graph neural network
- AutoML: automated recommendation, automated information extraction

Education

Texas A&M University, College Station, TX, USA

Sep 2019 – Dec 2023 (Expected)

Ph.D. students, Department of Computer Science & Engineering

Advisor: Prof. Xia (Ben) Hu

Beijing University of Posts and Telecommunications, Beijing, CHINA Sep 2016 – June 2019

M.S. in Computer Science Advisor: Prof. Chuan Shi

Shandong University, Jinan, Shandong, CHINA Sep 2011 – June 2015

B.S. in Information and Communication Engineering

Professional Experiences

Meta, Menlo Park, CA Sept 2022 – present

Research Intern

Understanding graph neural networks

Mentor: Qifan Wang

Snap Research, Seattle, WA May 2022 - Aug 2022

Research Intern

Efficient large-scale graph neural networks

Mentor: Neil Shah

Microsoft Research Asian (MSRA), Beijing, China

March 2019 - Jun 2019

Research Intern

Hyperparameter search with Bayesian optimization

Alibaba Group, Hangzhou, China

June 2018 - Sep 2018

Research Intern, Search Business Department

Query recommendation

Publications [Google Scholar]

[ICLR 2023] MLPInit: Embarrassingly Simple GNN Training Acceleration with MLP Initialization

Xiaotian Han, Tong Zhao, Yozen Liu, Xia Hu, Neil Shah

International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR), 2023

[ICML 2022] G-Mixup: Graph Augmentation for Graph Classification

Xiaotian Han, Zhimeng Jiang, Ninghao Liu, Xia Hu *International Conference on Machine Learning* (**ICML**), 2022

Outstanding Paper Award

^{*} indicates equal contribution.

[ICLR 2022] **Generalized Demographic Parity for Group Fairness**

Zhimeng Jiang, **Xiaotian Han**, Chao Fan, Fan Yang, Xia Hu,

International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR), 2022

Graph Representation Learning via Unsupervised Rate Reduction Maximization Xiaotian Han, Zhimeng Jiang, Ninghao Liu, Xia Hu

The Web Conference (WWW), 2022

[Recsys 2020] AutoRec: An Automated Recommender System

[WWW 2022]

Ting-Hsiang Wang, Qingquan Song, **Xiaotian Han**, Zirui Liu, Jin Haifeng, Xia Hu

ACM Conference on Recommender Systems (**Recsys**), 2020

[AAAI 2020] FlowScope: Spotting Money Laundering Based on Graphs,

Xiangfeng Li, Shenghua Liu, Zifeng Li, Xiaotian Han, Chuan Shi, Bryan Hooi, He Huang, Xueqi Cheng

AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI), 2020

Embedding Geographic Information for Anomalous Trajectory Detection [WWWJ 2020]

Ding Xiao, Li Song, Ruijia Wang, **Xiaotian Han**, Yanan Cai, Chuan Shi

World Wide Web, 2020

[KDD 2020] Metapath-guided Heterogeneous Graph Neural Network for Intent Recommendation

Shaohua Fan, Junxiong Zhu, **Xiaotian Han**, Chuan Shi, Linmei Hu, Biyu Ma, Yongliang Li

SIGKDD Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (KDD), 2019

[TKDE 2019] Deep Collaborative Filtering with Multi-aspect Information in Heterogeneous Networks

Chuan Shi, Xiaotian Han, Li Song, Xiao Wang, Senzhang Wang, Junping Du, Philip, S Yu

IEEE Transactions on Knowledge and Data Engineering (**TKDE**), 2019

[APWeb 2018] Representation Learning with Depth and Breadth for Recommendation using Multi-view Data

Xiaotian Han, Chuan Shi, Lei Zheng, Philip, S Yu, Jianxin Li, Yuanfu Lu

APWeb-WAIM International Joint Conference on Web and Big Data (APWeb-WAIM), 2018

Aspect-Level Deep Collaborative Filtering via Heterogeneous Information Networks [IJCAI 2018]

> Xiaotian Han, Chuan Shi, Senzhang Wang, Philip, S Yu, Li Song International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI), 2018

Anomalous Trajectory Detection Using Recurrent Neural Network [ADMA 2018]

Li Song, Ruijia Wang, Ding Xiao, **Xiaotian Han**, Yanan Cai, Chuan Shi

International Conference on Advanced Data Mining and Applications (ADMA), 2018

Best Paper Awards

[Under review] Do We Really Achieve Fairness with Explicit Sensitive Attributes?

Xiaotian Han, Zhimeng Jiang, Ninghao Liu, Na Zou, Qifan Wang, Xia Hu

2022

[Under review] Marginal Nodes Matter: Towards Structure Fairness in Graphs

Xiaotian Han, Kaixiong Zhou, Ting-Hsiang Wang, Jundong Li, Fei Wang, Na Zou

2022

[Under review] Retiring ΔDP : New Distribution-Level Metrics for Demographic Parity

Xiaotian Han*, Zhimeng Jiang*, Hongye Jin, Zirui Liu, Na Zou, Qifan Wang, Xia Hu

2022

[Under review] Fair Graph Message Passing with Transparency

Zhimeng Jiang, **Xiaotian Han**, Chao Fan, Zirui Liu, Na Zou, Ali Mostafavi, Xia Hu

2022

[Under review] Topology Matters in Fair Graph Learning: a Theoretical Pilot Study

Zhimeng Jiang, **Xiaotian Han**, Chao Fan, Zirui Liu, Xiao Huang, Na Zou, Ali Mostafavi, Xia Hu

2022

Professional Services

Program Committee Member/Reviewer

International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML)

Annual Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (**NeurIPS**)

AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI)

International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence(IJCAI)

The ACM Web Conference (**WWW**)

2022.2023 2022

2021,2022,2023

2021,2023

2023

ACM SIGKDD Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (KDD) International Conference on Data Mining (ICDM)	2023 2022
Volunteer International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML)	2022
Annual Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (NAACL)	2022
Session Chair International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML)	2022
Scholarships, Awards, & Honors	
Outstanding Paper Award, ICML2022 Travel Grant, Department of CSE, Texas A&M University, Travel Award, ICML2022 Outstanding Reviewer Award, ICML2022 Best Reviewer Award, CCF Transactions on Pervasive Computing and Interaction National Graduate Scholarship, Beijing University of Posts and Telecommunications Best Paper Awards, International Conference on Advanced Data Mining and Applications	2022 2022 2022 2022 2019 2018 2018

Last updated on February 16, 2023